so this is the only educational plan that
you can receive 100,000 yearly from
Age 2 until you are 17 and then
you can receive 200,000 yearly from
18 19 20 to 21 Hello guys I'm R Patrick
bas and I'm a financial advisor in man
philippines so I'm here to
discuss with you about manual
life Education builder so For sure
some of you may already have an idea about
education
plans or educational funding so
this manual life Education builder is
a type of educational plan so
let's find out what the benefits are that
you can get or the benefits that
your children can get if
you take them on an educational plan so
guys this is what I made a sample proposal
for manual life Education builder so
let's see what's in the
proposal and I'll also explain it quickly
in details so we can see man
life Education builder 10 minimum
minimum 10 years to pay so undertone the
variable unit linked product of vul  but
later you will know from vul How is
it going to be traditional or
guaranteed plan so later
you will know that so let's look at the
features determine the desired
annual Education benefit so it depends on
you the minimum is 150,000 every year
maybe by 18 19 2021 or there is also 5
years sc 22 So that example you chose
is the minimum is 150,000 But here in
our sample the
annual Education benefit we chose is 200,000
But others choose 250k 300k
500,000 so it depends on the budget so provide
yourself with the protection that you need
so the good thing here is that besides the
educational funds that can be saved in the plan
' Oh we also have insurance So that's the
good thing because for
example you are saving apart
from your savings but what but what if for
example something suddenly happens to you ' is that
our purpose Why did
we start this plan So if
something happens to happen it will still continue
to compare  If you
just saved, something happened to the client, let's say he
lost or was permanently disabled. Who will
continue? So that's the
advantage when you take this insurance plan, an
educational plan, so
next, secure yourself and your L ones
with additional protection, so
I'll discuss this later. I'll give you a
sample scenario so that it's clearer. I
chose the investment account that suits
your risk profile or investment time
frame. So we have many funds to
choose from. So before you take a
plan, you will
assign it to stocks or bonds. So increase your
investment if you wish or simply take
advantage of the optimistic market trend.
So anytime, in addition to what you put in
here, monthly, quarterly, semi-annually
or annually. Depending on your payment mode,
you can tap up at any time. So that's how you
increase your investment. For
example, you want to have extra money
today. I put 20k in the plan, which is an
addition to my investment fund in
my educational plan. So you can
do that. Anytime and then
you can do this anytime, but only for the
fifth year onwards, but hopefully if it's not
necessary, then don't worry.  just withdraw it
so withdraw from your account if needed
so it is stated if you just need it
So there are emergency cases like that um
Enjoy the reward of Keeping Your
investment with money life so if
for example um starting in the fifth year
the money is just there you don't
withdraw it of course
you just keep putting it in we will have a
2.5% bonus down on the average fund that
you have every 4 years So that's what we
call loyalty bonus so that's a waste '
and
then let's find out what the
benefits are because in the Information
you will see that the father is 40 years old
and then the child is 1 year old so in the
benefits So I mentioned earlier
there is life insurance which is 600,000
in our sample here and then the
contingent annual Education payout or this is what
the child will receive supposedly by
18 19 2021 or if the 5 years 5 years
course you chose until 22 so
200,000 each Year and then we also have
total disability  wavers So if
for example the parent is Matt totally
disabled so the payment will also be waived
and besides that there are
better benefits that
your child or you yourself will receive so next
we will show some sample scenarios
which are just two scenarios and
this is the one that will best explain what the
benefits are that you can
get from the man life occupation builder and
then the next scenario is the one that
really made our manual
life education builder palpitate but let
's first take scenario number one so
this is the scenario that is stated is the
parent is still alive so the child went to college
started college still alive and
then it also started Of course it will pay
out So we will see by the time the
father is 57 and then the child is 18 so
he started college
the payout is 200,000 and then by the next year
200,000 20 years old 200,000 again and
then next year or the last year 21 years
old  200,000 So that's a total of 800
100,000 that was paid out but that's only a 4 year
variant so we still have a 5
year variant Depending on the
plan the parent wants to take so by that
time the parent is 60 years old so it's possible that there will still be some
left over from the
account value or the fund value or the
investment fund of this plan even though it has
made a payout maybe there will still be some left over from the
investments and then Of course it depends on
the market So the parent can withdraw it
if he wants to enjoy the
money or can it be a partial withdrawal
first just reduce it then let
the money go because it's invested and
at least so that there is
still some payment for the cost of insurance so that
the life insurance of this
plan continues Even after the educational one is over So
at least it's an inheritance for the
future children and grandchildren I mean for the
future grandchildren of their children or
their own children so this plan
is set at a minimum of 10 years to pay
So um until 49 the parent pays
which is  He was 40 years old when he took it
so he just waited for the child to turn 1
to start the payout So
whatever school it is Okay so it can be used
Ong educational builder because it will
be given to you in cash so it's true if
for example the worst case scenario is
your child not going to school there is
still a spouse
who has invested and then the child turns 18 19 20 21 and
22 there will be a
payout that is the most basic
educational plan you will see that anywhere
but this scenario
number two of ours is what made it
special or why
this manual life Education builder is different from
other educational builders so let's find out
So this is scenario number
two this is the most special feature of the
manual life Education builder so
for example and it's only the second year of
payment If the father is gone or
permanently disabled So what will
the child receive because if in the
normal plan the
parent is gone or permanently disabled It's
either the plan will be lost or
the life insurance that the
plan has will be given But this
He is really working. Are you sure that every year,
okay, your child has education, so this is an
example. Number one child will receive
the Php600 which is the life insurance
here in our proposal. So in other plans,
you received the life insurance,
the plan is over. But this one, he doesn't
finish with life insurance,
that's just the beginning of the benefits, so
the Php600 was given because the
child's parent passed away, then it was
only in the second year, so in
our scenario, there was none, so the child was only 2 years old,
so two two going to three,
so he can receive it immediately. In addition to
the 600,000, you will receive the
php100,000
annually guaranteed. That's the
good thing about this plan. So after that,
you will receive it until 17 years old,
while he is a minor, and then by the
time he turns 18, which is when
he goes to college. In addition to the
100,000 he received every year,
he will receive the  200,000 yearly
annual Education payout which is from 18
19 20 to 21 so ' ba So many
benefits that your child can get
if you take them out of the
manual life Education builder and
hopefully you start this kind of
plan for your kids and then There
you can see I have calculated here in the upper
right 600,000 the life insurance total
of 1.6 million which became the um yearly
payout while the child was still a minor so in
our sample because the parent is not there immediately
and then 800,000
the total payout for College So that's
um total of php3 million The
benefits obtained here in the plan ' so ' is that
the manual Education builder is as good
as I was earlier in other plans you
just wave or you will receive the life
insurance But here it is waved that
you received the life insurance there are
still payouts starting at whatever age
the child is until he turns 21 that is
guaranteed that even high school
he has a budget and then especially for
college so hopefully
you understand the manual Education  builder
and if you still have questions,
maybe it would be better if we could talk
or you can send me a message or
email or through my messenger to
franchise,
send a message down on my Messenger so
we can concentrate faster
[Music]
their child